# Daniel Fernando Castañeda Torres

## Senior Front End Engineer

### Basic info:

**Phone:** 319 388 7076

Email: dfcastanedat@unal.edu.co

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/danicas99h-dev/

### Profile:

Bachelor of Computer and Systems Engineering, currently working as a Senior Front End Engineer, graduated with 4+ years of experience working with Vanilla JS, React.js and Angular projects, expertise in HTML (Accessibility and semantic) and CSS (BEM and SASS), good knowledge in Design Patterns (especially Structural and Behavioral patterns), global user state management libraries like Redux, global server state management like React Query. Experience and knowledge in both class-based components and function-based components in React.

#### Experience:

Publicis Global Delivery (August 2021 – Currently) – Senior Front End Engineer

One of the leaders of the new Interview Process within the company, reviewer of pull requests of internal projects using React.js and Remix. Currently working for Mercedes Benz as client for the company.

 Mercedes Benz Vans Upfitters: Work along with other 2 Principal Front End Engineers in a Vanilla JS and React.js app, focus on accessibility and optimization (Flux pattern mainly).

## Slabcode (January 2018 – July 2021) – Front End Developer

Began as a Junior Dev, left as Semi Senior dev reviewing pull requests and leading the React.js learning process within the company.

- WON Web: Web app, worked alone as a Front End, using HTML, CSS and JS (React.js)
- WON Admin: Web app, worked with a Junior Developer using HTML,
  CSS and JS (React.js)
- Relatoria SIC Admin: Web app, worked as a Semi Senior Dev alongside with another 2 Front end developers using HTML, CSS and TS (Angular), also use of RXJS and Bootstrap.
- Relatoria SIC Public: Web app, worked as Semi Senior Dev alone using HTML, CSS and JS (React.js).
- LavaloTú: Web App, worked as Semi Senior Dev using HTML, CSS, TS (Angular), RXJS, NgRX.
- Carrera 10K: Mobile app, worked as a Junior Dev using Kotlin.

#### **Education:**

Bachelor of Computer and Systems Engineering – Universidad Nacional de Colombia (2015-2020)

Bogotá, Colombia

## Skills:

- CSS/SCSS (5/5)
- HTML (5/5)
- Javascript (5/5)
- Typescript (4/5)
- React.js (5/5)
- Angular (4/5)

- Redux (5/5)
- Jest (4/5)
- React/Hook testing library (4/5)
- Docker (3/5)
- Git (4/5)

## Languages:

- Spanish (5/5)
- English (4/5)